CHAPTER 19: YOU JUST HAVE SUCH GOOD CHEMISTRY
19장: 정말 좋은 케미스트리를 갖고 계시군요
EPISODE 6
에피소드 6
This can't be real.
이것은 현실이 될 수 없습니다.
It's just a dream.
그것은 단지 꿈일 뿐입니다.
There's no way this is really happening.
이런 일이 실제로 일어날 리가 없습니다.
It just can't be.
그럴 수 없습니다.
I just want to die.
난 그냥 죽고 싶어요.
Why did it have to be him?
왜 그 사람이어야만 했나요?
I'm so embarrassed.
너무 부끄럽습니다.
This is so humiliating.
이건 정말 굴욕적인 일이에요.
Why is he still reading?
그 사람은 왜 아직도 책을 읽고 있는 걸까요?
Is he enjoying it?
그는 그것을 즐기고 있나요?
What?
무엇?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
What!
무엇!
He's supposed to be a genius. Is he a genius at torture too?
그 사람은 천재임에 틀림없어요. 그 사람도 고문의 천재인가요?
Making me die of humiliation without a single visible wound?
나를 굴욕감에 죽게 만들어 눈에 보이는 상처 하나 없이?
-Yeo Eui-ju. -Yes, sir?
-여의주. - 네, 선생님?
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
Sorry, sir?
죄송해요 선생님?
I asked what this is.
나는 이것이 무엇인지 물었다.
The thing is.
문제는입니다.
It looks like someone was working on a web novel.
누군가 같은데 웹소설을 작업하고 있었어요.
-Indeed. -Yes.
-물론. -예.
Yes, well.
네, 글쎄요.
I was pretty surprised myself.
나 자신도 꽤 놀랐다.
Gosh, that's just nasty…
맙소사, 정말 심술궂네…
It's not yours?
당신 것이 아니죠?
No, sir.
아니요, 선생님.
I didn't write it.
나는 그것을 쓰지 않았다.
Like someone who admits to drinking but denies drunk driving.
술을 인정한 사람처럼 하지만 음주운전은 부인한다.
You've been caught red-handed, yet you deny it?
당신은 적발되었습니다. 그런데 당신은 그것을 부정합니까?
The clueless Korean lit. major Choi Yoon is Dong-ju.
무지한 한국어가 켜졌습니다. 최윤 소령 동주예요.
The complete asshole…
완전 병신...
of a math genius Ju Si-on is me.
수학천재 주시온이 나다.
The dumb sports major Kang Tae-ha,
멍청한 스포츠 전공 강태하,
who solves everything with force, is Gi-jeon.
힘으로 모든 것을 해결하는 사람, 기전이에요.
And Han Jae-min, who comes from Japan and is loaded,
그리고 한재민, 일본에서 와서 짐을 실은 사람,
is Da-ju.
다주입니다.
No.
아니요.
How did you come to that conclusion?
어떻게 그런 결론을 내리셨나요?
"I didn't realize you were such a lost cause."
"몰랐어. 당신은 정말 잃어버린 원인이었습니다."
"I'm very disappointed."
"매우 실망했어요."
"It was clearly your fault and you've admitted it."
"분명히 네 잘못이야. 그리고 너도 인정했잖아."
"All that's left is compensation."
"남은 것은 보상뿐이다."
"Breaking my glasses caused ten million won's worth of damage."
"안경이 깨져서 생긴 일이야. 피해액 천만 원"
"You'll have to find another way to repay me."
"다른 방법을 찾아야 해. 나한테 갚으려고."
All that being word for word what I said is a coincidence?
내가 말한 모든 것은 한마디로 표현된 것입니다. 우연인가?
"You wouldn't let him sleep. Don't you know he's a sleepyhead?"
"당신은 그 사람을 잠들게 하지 않을 거예요. 그 사람 잠꾸러기인 거 모르세요?"
Da-ju said that in the car on the way to school.
다주가 차에서 그러더군요 학교 가는 길.
Is this all just a coincidence?
이 모든 것이 단지 우연일까요?
Or is my imagination running wild?
아니면 나의 상상력이 날뛰고 있는 걸까?
You just have such good chemistry.
당신은 정말 좋은 케미스트리를 가지고 있습니다.
What?
무엇?
You all have such good chemistry.
다들 케미스트리가 너무 좋으세요.
So I just wrote about it.
그래서 그냥 그것에 대해 썼습니다.
But the thing is…
하지만 문제는...
People really liked it, so…
사람들이 정말 좋아해서…
Even if you can't tell right from wrong, still…
말할 수는 없어도 옳고 그름, 아직도…
There's a line you shouldn't cross.
넘지 말아야 할 선이 있습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Delete it.
삭제하세요.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
I can't, sir.
저는 할 수 없습니다.
You can't?
당신은 할 수 없습니다?
No, I can't.
아니요, 그럴 수 없습니다.
I can't.
나는 할 수 없다.
Please forgive me.
용서해주세요.
I really can't delete it.
정말 삭제할 수가 없어요.
I'm really sorry. It was a mistake, but I can't delete it.
정말 죄송해요. 실수였어, 하지만 삭제할 수는 없습니다.
You base your characters on your teachers
당신의 캐릭터는 선생님을 기반으로 합니다
and even have them say things I can't even bring myself to say.
심지어 그들이 말하게 하기도 해요 나는 말할 수조차 없습니다.
How can I let that slide?
어떻게 하면 미끄러지도록 할 수 있나요?
Put yourself in my position.
내 입장이 되어 보세요.
Even so.
비록 그렇다 하더라도.
I can't delete it.
삭제할 수 없습니다.
I really can't.
난 정말 할 수 없습니다.
Fine.
괜찮은.
Then I will.
그럼 그럴게요.
PASSWORD
비밀번호
Enter your password.
비밀번호를 입력하세요.
Mr. Ga.
가씨
I'll study really hard.
정말 열심히 공부하겠습니다.
I'll study math really hard.
나는 수학을 정말 열심히 공부할 것이다.
Please, give me a break.
제발 좀 쉬게 해주세요.
Even the dying get one last wish.
죽어가는 사람도 마지막 소원을 하나 얻습니다.
Can't you do one favor to help out a pitiful student?
부탁 하나만 들어줄 수 없나요 불쌍한 학생을 돕기 위해?
I put my life and soul into writing it.
나는 그것을 쓰는 데 내 삶과 영혼을 바쳤습니다.
How can I just delete it?
어떻게 하면 그냥 삭제할 수 있나요?
Please cut me a break.
잠시 휴식을 취해주세요.
I really can't delete it.
정말 삭제할 수가 없어요.
I can't delete it.
삭제할 수 없습니다.
Please.
제발.
What am I going to do?
나는 무엇을 할 것인가?
I'm so sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
30 MINUTES LATER
30분 후
If you really can't delete it,
정말 삭제할 수 없다면
bring your parents to see me.
부모님을 모시고 오세요.
-Sorry? -If you're okay
-죄송합니다? -괜찮다면
with your parents, the principal,
부모님, 교장 선생님과 함께
the faculty and all the students knowing what you've been up to.
교수진과 학생 모두 당신이 무슨 일을 했는지 알고 있는 거죠.
No, sir.
아니요, 선생님.
My mom will kill me.
엄마가 나를 죽일거야.
It seems you know what you've done is wrong.
아시는 것 같군요 당신이 한 일은 잘못되었습니다.
Why do you want to keep doing something you can't tell anyone about?
왜 계속 뭔가를 하고 싶은가? 아무한테도 말하면 안 돼?
I'm going to check tomorrow, so either delete it or bring your parents.
내일 확인해 봐야겠어요, 그러니 삭제하거나 부모님을 모셔오세요.
Sir!
선생님!
CHAPTER 20: THE OBSESSIVE TOP DOESN'T EVEN HAVE A TOILET IN HIS BATHROOM
20장: 강박적인 탑은 심지어 욕실에 화장실이 있어요
I'm home.
나는 집에있다.
I made galbijjim.
갈비찜을 만들었어요.
I'm not hungry.
나는 배고프지 않다.
What's wrong? Are you sick?
무슨 일이야? 당신은 아픈가요?
No.
아니요.
Shall I make you tteokbokki instead?
대신 떡볶이 만들어 드릴까요?
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
Shall I delete it?
삭제할까요?
No, I can't.
아니요, 그럴 수 없습니다.
Then everyone will find out what I wrote.
그러면 모두가 내가 쓴 것을 알게 될 것입니다.
Still, isn't that better than deleting it?
그래도 지우는 것보다는 낫지 않나?
Am I crazy? It's better to delete it.
내가 미쳤나요? 삭제하시는 것이 좋습니다.
-You're home? -Yeah.
- 집에 왔어요? -응.
-Hey.
-여기요.
Tae-ha caressed Yoon's snow-white skin…
태하가 윤의 새하얀 피부를 어루만졌다…
tenderly.
다정하게.
Hey! Sit apart.
여기요! 떨어져 앉으십시오.
I said sit apart.
나는 떨어져 앉으라고 말했다.
-What's wrong? -You startled me.
- 무슨 일이야? -당신은 나를 놀라게 했어요.
Wanna play?
놀고 싶어?
No, I can't.
아니요, 그럴 수 없습니다.
-Just one round. -No, I need to get to bed.
- 한 라운드만요. -아니요, 자러 가야 해요.
I know you want to.
나는 당신이 원한다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
Just a quickie.
그냥 빨리요.
Wanna
싶어
-play? -Just a quickie.
-놀다? - 잠깐만요.
Let me join in.
저도 동참하겠습니다.
-The three of us? -Move.
- 우리 셋이요? -이동하다.
Was it leg day today? Nice.
오늘 다리의 날이었나요? 멋진.
No.
아니요.
Not two of you, nor three of you.
두 명도 아니고 세 명도 아닙니다.
Just play by yourself.
그냥 혼자 놀아보세요.
What do you mean play by ourselves?
우리끼리 놀아요은 무슨 뜻인가요?
What's wrong with you?
왜 그래?
You want to play too? We can change partners.
너도 놀고 싶어? 우리는 파트너를 바꿀 수 있습니다.
I'm disgusting.
나는 역겹다.
My mind. My imagination.
내 마음. 나의 상상.
What on earth was all that?
도대체 그게 다 뭐였지?
BOYS' LOVE
소년들의 사랑
This is for all teachers and students.
이는 모든 교사와 학생을 위한 것입니다.
Just to inform you that eleventh-grader Yeo Eui-ju
단지 당신에게 알리기 위해 그 11학년 여의주
has been writing a BL web novel titled We Were Friends.
BL 웹소설을 집필하고 있습니다 제목은 우리는 친구였다.
BL?
BL?
You told me you didn't like that. Were you lying?
당신은 그것이 마음에 들지 않는다고 말했습니다. 거짓말하고 있었나요?
Go-ya!
가-야!
Disgusting.
역겨운.
Pretending to be all sweet and innocent.
다정하고 순진한 척.
Why pair a guy with another guy?
왜 한 남자를 다른 남자와 짝을 이루나요?
-No. -Eui-ju.
-아니요. -의주.
Mom.
엄마.
What's wrong?
무슨 일이야?
Mom, I…
엄마, 저는...
This is a crime.
이것은 범죄입니다.
You've tarnished my name and my honor.
당신은 내 이름과 명예를 더럽혔습니다.
I hope you rot in jail.
감옥에서 썩기를 바랍니다.
I made a mistake.
제가 실수를 했습니다.
Are you crazy?
제정신이에요?
Idle hands are the devil's playthings.
게으른 손은 악마의 장난감이다.
It gives me the creeps.
그것은 나에게 소름 끼치는 일을 준다.
Eui-ju.
의주.
No.
아니요.
No, sir.
아니요, 선생님.
It's not like that.
그렇지 않습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
My daughter didn't do anything wrong.
내 딸은 아무 잘못도 하지 않았습니다.
She learned from me.
그녀는 나에게서 배웠습니다.
-It's all my fault. -Dad…
- 다 내 잘못이에요. -아빠...
No!
아니요!
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
Let me go!
날 보내줘!
Don't come any closer.
더 이상 가까이 오지 마세요.
No.
아니요.
I must never be outed.
나는 절대 아웃팅되어서는 안 된다.
It seems you know what you've done is wrong.
아시는 것 같군요 당신이 한 일은 잘못되었습니다.
Why do you want to keep doing something you can't tell anyone about?
왜 계속 뭔가를 하고 싶은가? 아무한테도 말하면 안 돼?
Boys' love…
소년들의 사랑...
"The character with the biggest fan base is the obsessive exhibitionist."
"가장 큰 팬층을 보유한 캐릭터 강박적인 노출증 환자야."
"He lives in a marble penthouse where the lights are always off."
"그는 대리석 펜트하우스에 산다. 불이 항상 꺼져 있는 곳."
"He's cut ties with his family and has no friends."
"그는 가족과의 관계를 끊었어요. 그리고 친구도 없어."
"When he showers, he only ever uses the rain shower head."
"그가 샤워할 때, 그 사람은 레인 샤워기 헤드만 사용해요."
"In his bathroom, there's…"
"그의 화장실에는…"
NO TOILET
화장실 없음
"…no toilet?"
"…화장실은 없나요?"
Why not?
왜 안 돼?
Why did I have to get caught
왜 내가 잡힐 수밖에 없었나
by that asshole of a math teacher?
그 멍청한 수학 선생님 때문에?
Ga Woo-su!
가우수님!
Good morning.
좋은 아침이에요.
Follow me.
나를 따르라.
COUNSELING IN PROGRESS
상담 진행 중
Did you delete it?
삭제하셨나요?
Mr. Ga.
가씨
I started writing web novels when I was in eighth grade.
웹소설을 쓰기 시작했어요 내가 8학년이었을 때.
And?
그리고?
It was just a crappy story I made by cobbling together bits and pieces I liked.
그냥 내가 만든 진부한 이야기였어 내가 좋아하는 조각과 조각을 함께 엮는 것.
But I decided to upload it to the Challenge League.
하지만 업로드하기로 결정했습니다. 챌린지 리그로.
Then, out of the blue, it got
그런데 갑자기
two favorites.
즐겨찾기 두 개.
I got so excited that I did a mass release of two more episodes.
너무 신나서 그랬어 나는 두 개의 에피소드를 더 대량 출시했습니다.
What I mean by that
그게 무슨 뜻이야
is in quick succession.
빠르게 연속되고 있습니다.
You have to be quick with the first few episodes to generate
당신은 빨리해야합니다 생성할 처음 몇 개의 에피소드
a buzz.
윙윙거리는 소리.
Anyhow, the number of favorites
어쨌든 즐겨찾기 수
went straight back down to one.
바로 다시 1번으로 내려갔습니다.
They must have seen the next two episodes
다음 두 에피소드를 본 게 틀림없어
and done a runner.
그리고 주자를 완료했습니다.
10 MINUTES LATER
10분 후
These days, do you know what I think
요즘 내 생각이 어떤지 아세요
when I wake up in the morning?
아침에 일어났을 때?
I can see the light at the end of the tunnel.
나는 빛을 볼 수 있습니다 터널 끝에서.
What I thought was a dead-end cave was actually a tunnel.
막다른 동굴인줄 알았던 곳 실제로는 터널이었습니다.
The cold and lonely winter
춥고 외로운 겨울
is finally coming to an end and flowers are going to bloom.
드디어 끝나가네 그리고 꽃이 피어날 거예요.
Mr. Ga, this novel
가씨 이 소설
gives me hope and is a dream I can't give up.
나에게 희망을 준다 그리고 포기할 수 없는 꿈이에요.
Can you please help me make my dream come true?
저를 도와주세요 내 꿈을 이뤄줄까?
Can you please help me finish my novel?
내 소설을 끝내는 것을 도와주실 수 있나요?
No.
아니요.
Just this once.
이번 한 번만요.
Just this once, please.
이번 한 번만 부탁드립니다.
Are you saying you intend to keep writing the sort of things I would never say?
계속 글을 쓸 생각이라는 건가요? 내가 절대 말하지 않을 그런 종류의 말?
The sort of stuff that gives me the ick and sets my teeth on edge?
나에게 짜증을 주는 종류의 것들 내 이빨이 곤두선다고?
Are you crying?
울고 있나요?
No, sir.
아니요, 선생님.
I know I did wrong.
나는 내가 잘못했다는 것을 안다.
But how can I delete it? It's got more than 20,000 favorites.
그런데 어떻게 삭제할 수 있나요? 즐겨찾기 수가 20,000개가 넘습니다.
Anyone would think I'm the bad guy here. I'm the victim!
누구든지 내가 여기서 나쁜 사람이라고 생각할 것입니다. 내가 피해자야!
Of all the different genres,
다양한 장르 중에서
why did it have to be BL?
왜 BL이어야만 했나요?
Because the more I heard "No, no," the more I want to encourage them,
왜냐면 "아니, 아니"라는 말을 더 많이 들었기 때문입니다. 그들을 격려하고 싶을수록
and even just the slightest brush of a fingertip creates a deep yearning.
그리고 아주 작은 붓이라도 손끝 하나가 깊은 그리움을 만들어낸다.
Do you even know what you did wrong?
당신은 당신이 무엇을 잘못했는지 알고 있나요?
Yes, I do.
네, 그렇습니다.
I do know.
나는 알고 있다.
But if you look at it from a more worldly point-of-view, love is love.
하지만 좀 더 세상적인 시각으로 보면 관점에서 보면 사랑은 사랑이다.
When two people love each other, gender isn't that important.
두 사람이 서로 사랑할 때, 성별은 그다지 중요하지 않습니다.
Not that.
그렇지 않습니다.
Not that?
그거 아니지?
Then, the raunchiness?
그럼 그 야릇함은?
But it's not even rated 15.
하지만 15등급도 되지 않았습니다.
Even the publisher said it's mild.
출판사에서도 온화하다고 하더군요.
Mild!
경증!
Not that either?
그것도 아니지?
Making my teachers the main characters?
선생님을 주인공으로 만들까요?
Yes, that was a huge mistake on my part.
네, 그건 제 큰 실수였습니다.
And I'm really sorry about that, but--
그 점은 정말 죄송하지만--
You really are a lost cause.
당신은 정말로 잃어버린 원인입니다.
You still don't know what you did wrong.
당신은 아직도 자신이 무엇을 잘못했는지 모릅니다.
How can you not know?
어떻게 알 수 없나요?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I just don't get it.
나는 그것을 이해하지 못한다.
How is it?
어때요?
Why on earth…
도대체 왜...
Am I not the main character?
나는 주인공이 아닌가?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
You're going to have Dong-ju and Gi-jeon end up together.
동주랑 기전이 있을 거야 함께 끝나요.
Where does that leave me?
그러면 나는 어디로 가는가?
You're a sub character.
당신은 서브 캐릭터입니다.
A sub.
서브.
I've never been a sub my whole life.
나는 평생 서브로 살아본 적이 없습니다.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
I want you to rewrite it.
다시 써주셨으면 합니다.
With me
나와 함께
as the main character.
주인공으로.
-What? -You know what the main character is.
-무엇? -주인공이 무엇인지 아시나요?
You want to be the obsessive top?
강박적인 최고가되고 싶습니까?
If that's the main character.
그게 주인공이라면.
Then the story will go off the rails.
그러면 이야기가 궤도에서 벗어나게 됩니다.
I don't care if it jumps the shark,
상어를 뛰어넘어도 상관없어
just know that I'm going to check each and every episode.
내가 확인해 볼 것이라는 것만 알아두세요 에피소드마다.
Sir, you can't check it in advance. I simply can't allow it.
선생님, 미리 확인하실 수는 없습니다. 도저히 허락할 수가 없습니다.
Why not?
왜 안 돼?
Well…
글쎄… ​​
If I know you're going to be reading,
당신이 책을 읽을 것이라는 것을 안다면,
how can I write that kind of stuff?
어떻게 그런 글을 쓸 수 있지?
Then delete it.
그런 다음 삭제하십시오.
You have two choices.
두 가지 선택이 있습니다.
Delete it or let me check each episode.
삭제하시거나 각 회차를 확인하겠습니다.
What are you going to do?
당신은 무엇을 할 예정입니까?
I'll do it.
내가 할게요.
I'll let you check it.
확인하도록 할게요.
What am I going to do?
나는 무엇을 할 것인가?
So he's mad, not because it's BL,
그래서 그는 화를 냈습니다. BL이기 때문이 아닙니다.
but because he isn't the main character?
그런데 그 사람이 주인공이 아니라서?
He's not normal.
그는 정상이 아닙니다.
He must be crazy.
그 사람은 미친 게 분명해요.
EBC FILMING PROPOSAL
EBC 촬영 제안
CHAPTER 21: YOU REALLY THINK WOO-SU WILL DO IT?
21장: 정말 우수가 할 거라고 생각해요?
3. OBJECTIVE
3. 목적
Come in.
들어오세요.
Do come in.
꼭 들어오세요.
Have a seat.
앉으세요.
Take a look.
보세요.
EBC is coming here to film?
EBC가 촬영하러 여기에 온다고요?
Finally.
마지막으로.
Next Monday, the makers of that hit program
다음주 월요일, 그 인기 프로그램 제작자
are coming to film at our school.
우리 학교에 영화 보러 와요.
You four teachers are the pride of our school.
선생님 네 분 우리 학교의 자랑이에요.
You're all elite teachers with impressive resumes.
여러분은 모두 엘리트 선생님이십니다. 인상적인 이력서와 함께.
When you're filmed teaching the kids with your endless passion and dedication,
아이들을 가르치는 장면을 찍을 때 당신의 끝없는 열정과 헌신으로
the foundation's donors are sure to start writing checks, right, Dong-ju?
재단의 기부자들은 확신합니다 수표 쓰기 시작하는 거 맞지, 동주?
Sorry? Me?
죄송합니다? 나?
I want you to write an essay setting out your philosophy of education.
에세이를 써줬으면 좋겠어 교육철학을 제시합니다.
One that elicits emotion.
감정을 이끌어내는 사람.
Enough to make people cry.
사람들을 울게 만들기에 충분합니다.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
And as for you, Gi-jeon.
그리고 기전 너도.
Prepare a few words about your path
당신의 길에 대해 몇 마디 준비하세요
from retiring as a professional athlete to become a teacher.
프로 운동선수 은퇴 후 선생님이 되려고.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
-Next, Da-ju. -Yes.
-다음은 다주. -예.
Do you think you can rehash
다시 해칠 수 있다고 생각하세요
your TUD talk?
TUD 얘기요?
Your grand vision is sure to go down in history.
당신의 원대한 비전 반드시 역사에 남을 것입니다.
-Down in history.
-역사 속으로.
And last but not least, Woo-su.
그리고 마지막으로 우수님.
What more needs to be said?
무슨 말이 더 필요합니까?
You're the very definition of a global elite.
당신은 바로 정의입니다 글로벌 엘리트의.
We just need to change your glasses.
안경만 바꾸면 됩니다.
-And in class-- -I won't be taking part.
-그리고 수업시간에는-- -저는 참여하지 않겠습니다.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
I don't want to film.
나는 영화를 찍고 싶지 않습니다.
But I'll cooperate in another way if there's any.
하지만 다른 방법으로 협력하겠습니다. 있다면.
Woo-su.
우수.
I guess you didn't hear me.
내 말을 듣지 못한 것 같아요.
This program will be on EBC.
이 프로그램은 EBC에서 방송됩니다.
If you don't agree to film,
촬영에 동의하지 않으면
that's going to be a problem.
그것은 문제가 될 것입니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
That won't be possible.
그건 불가능합니다.
Still, for the sake of the school's future development,
그래도 ~를 위해서 학교의 미래 발전,
please take some time to reconsider.
잠시 시간을 내어 다시 생각해 보시기 바랍니다.
I believe I've made myself clear.
나는 나 자신을 분명히했다고 믿습니다.
If you've nothing more to say, I'll be on my way.
더 이상 할 말이 없다면, 난 곧 갈게.
Don't worry, Ms. Kim.
걱정하지 마세요, 김 선생님.
I'll convince him.
제가 그를 설득하겠습니다.
Da-ju.
다주.
If you wouldn't mind.
괜찮으시다면요.
I want the four of you
네 명을 원해
including Woo-su to be on camera.
우수를 비롯해 카메라에 담길 예정이다.
There's a week until filming, I'm sure you can do it.
촬영까지 일주일 남았는데, 나는 당신이 그것을 할 수 있다고 확신합니다.
-Yes. -Of course.
-예. -물론.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
What are you going to do?
당신은 무엇을 할 예정입니까?
Got any ideas?
어떤 아이디어가 있나요?
Of course, he doesn't.
물론 그는 그렇지 않습니다.
Couldn't just the three of us do it?
우리 셋이서만 할 수는 없나요?
You heard what the principal said.
교장 선생님이 말씀하시는 걸 들었잖아요.
There's no point without Woo-su.
우수가 없으면 아무 의미가 없다.
We're basically Ga Woo-su and Boys.
저희는 기본적으로 가우수와 아이들이에요.
You really think Woo-su will do it?
정말 우수가 할 거라고 생각해요?
You know him better than anyone.
당신은 누구보다 그를 더 잘 알고 있습니다.
Why did you say you'd convince him?
왜 그를 설득하겠다고 했죠?
At this school,
이 학교에서는
upsetting the principal
교장을 화나게 하다
is a fate worse than death.
죽음보다 더 나쁜 운명이다.
If Woo-su won't film,
우수수가 촬영을 안 하면
we'll all end up being fired.
우리 모두는 결국 해고될 거예요.
No way.
안 돼요.
You think?
당신 생각에는?
Hey, Woo-su.
안녕, 우수.
Not doing it.
하지 않습니다.
Just this once.
이번 한 번만요.
It'll be over in no time.
곧 끝날 거예요.
How can you even say that?
어떻게 그런 말을 할 수 있나요?
You of all people.
모든 사람들의 당신.
You think I want to do this?
내가 이걸 하고 싶어할 것 같아?
I've known you since third grade.
나는 당신을 3학년 때부터 알았습니다.
I know what happened better than anyone.
나는 무슨 일이 일어났는지 누구보다 잘 알고 있다.
Then don't make me say it again.
그럼 다시는 말하게 하지 마세요.
Get out.
나가세요.
Woo-su, don't make me get down on my knees and beg.
우수야, 나한테 그러지 마 무릎을 꿇고 빌겠습니다.
Don't bother. Now get out.
귀찮게 하지 마세요. 이제 나가세요.
Fine.
괜찮은.
WE WERE FRIENDS
우리는 친구였어
WE WERE FRIENDS, EPISODE 3
우리는 친구였어, 에피소드 3
When is she going to upload episode four?
4화는 언제 업로드할 예정인가요?
CHAPTER 22: DO I REALLY HAVE TO CHANGE THIS FOR YOU TO FEEL VALIDATED?
22장: 정말 변화해야 하는가? 이것이 당신이 타당하다고 느끼도록 하기 위한 것인가요?
Now that he's going to check my work,
이제 그 사람이 내 작업을 확인하려고 하니
how am I supposed to write all the flirty stuff?
내가 어떻게 글을 써야 하지? 모든 유혹적인 것들?
I refuse to breathe until we get episode four!
나는 숨을 거부한다 에피소드 4가 나올 때까지!
Do you feel the tension between these two?
이 둘 사이의 긴장감을 느끼시나요?
Hurry up and upload episode four!
서둘러서 4화를 업로드해주세요!
When is episode four coming out?
4화는 언제 나오나요?
Where's episode four?
에피소드 4는 어디에 있나요?
Where's the "mass release"? Have you lost your spark?
"대량 출시"는 어디에 있습니까? 불꽃을 잃었나요?
I'm sorry, sir.
죄송합니다.
There's no need to apologize to me.
나한테 사과할 필요는 없어요.
Try to understand how Si-on feels.
시온의 심정을 이해하려고 노력해보세요.
What he likes and how he grew up.
그가 무엇을 좋아하는지, 어떻게 성장했는지.
What he thinks about Yoon.
그가 윤에 대해 어떻게 생각하는지.
Concentrate on Si-on.
시온에게 집중하세요.
I hear EBC is gonna film at school.
EBC가 학교에서 촬영할 거라고 들었어요.
I hope Dong-ju doesn't become famous.
동주가 유명해지지 않았으면 좋겠다.
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
MATHEMATICS
수학
Why do you get nervous and run away every time you see Mr. Ga?
왜 긴장해서 도망가는 거야? 가씨를 볼 때마다?
Me?
나?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
No, I don't.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
-Where did we get to? -We're up to page 101.
-우리는 어디로 갔나요? -101페이지까지 왔어요.
Page 101.
101페이지.
Velocity and acceleration.
속도와 가속도.
He's so hardcore.
그 사람은 정말 하드코어해요.
How can he ride her like that just for getting four points?
어떻게 그 사람이 그녀를 그렇게 탈 수 있지? 단지 4점을 얻기 위해서?
A lot of kids gave up on math.
많은 아이들이 수학을 포기했습니다.
But Eui-ju's the only one that took the bait.
하지만 의주뿐이야 그것은 미끼를 잡았습니다.
It's not just the after-school class. She seems to be really stressed.
방과후 수업만이 아닙니다. 그녀는 정말 스트레스를 받은 것 같습니다.
WE WERE FRIENDS, EPISODE 4
우리는 친구였어, 에피소드 4
THE DOOR TO THE PENTHOUSE OPENS TO REVEAL A LONG CORRIDOR
펜트하우스의 문이 열립니다 긴 복도를 공개하려면
HIS HAND CLUTCHING THE STRAP ON HIS BAG, YOON APPROACHES TAE-HA
그의 손은 가방 끈을 꼭 쥐고 있고, 윤이 태하에게 접근하다
I told you not to be late. Not even a second.
내가 늦지 말라고 했잖아. 1초도 안 됐어요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I ran here so as not to be late.
나는 늦지 않기 위해 여기로 달려갔다.
Were you with Si-on?
시온이랑 같이 있었어?
YOON COULDN'T BRING HIMSELF TO ANSWER
윤은 스스로 대답하지 못했다
HIS SILENCE WAS ENOUGH OF AN ANSWER
그의 침묵만으로도 대답은 충분했다
This won't do.
이건 안 돼요.
Choi Yoon.
최윤.
This place is huge.
이곳은 거대합니다.
You live here alone?
여기 혼자 살아요?
What about that ten million?
그 천만은 어떻습니까?
Why are you being like this, Tae-ha?
태하야 왜 그러는 거야?
This isn't you.
이 사람은 당신이 아닙니다.
I'm not the same guy who hung on your every word.
나는 같은 사람이 아니다 당신의 모든 말에 매달린 사람.
who ran to you like a puppy.
강아지처럼 당신에게 달려온 사람.
Not anymore.
더 이상은 아닙니다.
Tae-ha.
태하.
No.
아니요.
I could be
나는
your puppy.
당신의 강아지.
From now on,
이제부터
I'll be your personal bitch.
나는 당신의 개인적인 여자가 될 것입니다.
FROM NOW ON, I'LL BE YOUR PERSONAL BITCH
이제부터 내가 너의 개인적인 여자가 될게
I made the right choice.
나는 올바른 선택을 했습니다.
This is better than deleting it.
삭제하는 것보다 이게 낫습니다.
When faced with a difficult choice,
어려운 선택에 직면했을 때,
taking the more difficult path
더 어려운 길을 택해
is the way to salvation.
구원에 이르는 길이다.
No, I'm dying here.
아니, 난 여기서 죽어가고 있어요.
If it's the penthouse,
펜트하우스라면
shouldn't that be where Si-on lives?
거기가 시온이 사는 곳이 아니겠지?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
What did I say?
내가 뭐라고 말했나요?
Si-on should be the main character.
시온이 주인공이 되어야죠.
Again.
다시.
Right. From now on,
오른쪽. 이제부터
Si-on is the obsessive lead and Tae-ha the regretful sub.
시온은 강박적인 주인공이다. 그리고 아쉬운 서브 태하.
Give all the key impactful lines to Si-on.
임팩트 있는 핵심 대사는 모두 시온에게 맡겨주세요.
Rewrite it with Tae-ha's role minimized.
태하 역할을 최소화해서 다시 써보세요.
Now.
지금.
Here?
여기?
You've got one hour.
한 시간 남았습니다.
Get away from him.
그에게서 떨어져.
What?
무엇?
It can't be helped if you've got feelings for Tae-ha.
어쩔 수 없지 태하를 향한 마음이 있다면.
But I won't stand idly by.
하지만 가만히 있지는 않을 거예요.
From now on,
이제부터
I'll be your personal bitch.
나는 당신의 개인적인 여자가 될 것입니다.
Hang on a second.
잠깐만요.
This feels wrong.
이건 잘못된 것 같아요.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
What's wrong?
무슨 일이야?
Shouldn't this be Tae-ha's line?
이건 태하의 대사가 아닐까?
I know it feels a little awkward.
조금 어색한 느낌이라는 걸 알아요.
Still, let's stick with it.
그래도 계속해서 버텨보자.
Yoon needs to realize Si-on isn't the one.
윤은 시온이 그 사람이 아니라는 것을 깨달아야 한다.
This isn't the first time he's been gaslit.
이번이 처음이 아니다 그는 화를 냈습니다.
It's really frustrating.
정말 답답해요.
That needs to happen for Si-on to go tumbling head over heels in misery.
시온이가려면 그런 일이 일어나야 해 비참함 속에서 머리를 굴러다니는 것.
At this rate, he won't even manage a single roly-poly.
이 속도로, 그는 심지어 하나의 롤리폴리도 관리하지 않을 것입니다.
But, more than that,
하지만 그보다 더 중요한 것은
aren't I the lead character?
내가 주인공이 아니지?
Right now, Si-on is coming across as the obsessive top.
지금 시온이 찾아오고 있어요 강박적인 정상으로.
Not at all.
별말씀을요.
No way. Of course not.
안 돼요. 물론 그렇지 않습니다.
It's just, as I was writing it,
그냥 제가 쓰던대로 입니다.
I felt like I should change the flow of the narrative.
나도 변해야겠다는 생각이 들었어 이야기의 흐름.
In that way, how can I put it…
그런 식으로 말하면 어떻게 표현할까요…
The characters will go through a wider range of emotions,
캐릭터들이 지나가겠죠 더 넓은 범위의 감정
and the story itself will be more diverse.
이야기 자체도 더욱 다양해질 것입니다.
But the thing is…
하지만 문제는...
Just a moment.
잠시만요.
Do I really have to change this for you to feel validated?
정말 이걸 바꿔야 하나? 당신이 인정받았다고 느끼기 위해서요?
Fine.
괜찮은.
You're doing great.
당신은 잘하고 있습니다.
Fine, now if everybody
좋아, 이제 모두
can just hang in there!
그냥 거기에 버틸 수 있어요!
-Let's get back to it. -Okay.
-다시 돌아가자. -좋아요.
-Let's do this. -From the top.
- 이렇게 해보자. -위에서.
I'm fine with that.
난 괜찮아요.
-We're doing this again? -From now on,
- 우리 또 이러는 거야? -지금부터
I'm going to be your personal bitch.
나는 당신의 개인 나쁜 년이 될 것입니다.
Is this right?
이게 맞나요?
What the heck? I can't even write my own novel how I want.
도대체 뭐야? 글도 못쓰는데 내가 원하는 대로 나만의 소설.
Hang on.
잠깐만요.
He's only checking the original file.
그는 원본 파일만 확인하고 있습니다.
That's much better.
그게 훨씬 낫습니다.
Really?
정말?
Upload it.
업로드하세요.
WE WERE FRIENDS EPISODE 4 REAL
우리는 친구였습니다 에피소드 4 실제
SUBMIT A NEW PROJECT
새로운 프로젝트 제출
WE WERE FRIENDS, EPISODE 4
우리는 친구였어, 에피소드 4
There's no way he'll check online.
그가 온라인으로 확인할 방법은 없습니다.
Like he'd ever look up We Were Friends.
마치 그가 We Were Friends를 찾아본 적이 있는 것처럼 말입니다.
-Not him. -You little…
-그 사람은 아니야. - 꼬마야...
Today's the day.
오늘이 바로 그 날이다.
Check your students' uniforms
학생들의 교복을 확인하세요
and make sure they're on their best behavior.
그리고 확실히 해라 그들은 최선을 다하고 있습니다.
Let's make sure this is a success.
이것이 성공했는지 확인해 봅시다.
-What's going on? -Film him on the sly?
- 무슨 일이에요? -그를 몰래 촬영한다고요?
I'll keep it a secret.
비밀로 할게요.
I know everything.
나는 모든 것을 알고 있습니다.
If you're not going to cooperate, you leave me no choice.
협조하지 않겠다면, 당신은 나에게 선택의 여지가 없습니다.
Why are you going this far? You're going to regret this.
왜 이렇게까지 가나요? 당신은 이것을 후회하게 될 것입니다.
Are you going to betray my trust?
내 믿음을 배반할 건가요?
-I'll figure it out by myself. -Try that, then.
- 제가 직접 해결하겠습니다. - 그럼 시도해 보세요.
What am I going to do now, Mr. Ga?
가 선생님, 저는 이제 어떻게 해야 합니까?
Shall I just transfer?
그냥 옮겨볼까?
Subtitle: Paul Carver
부제: 폴 카버